Thank you for coming, Thorn Princess.
恭候多时了 荆棘公主
Hello. The garden is as beautiful as always.
您好 花园还是一如既往地美丽呢
- Shopkeeper. - It is, isn't it?
-店长 -是吧?
With proper watering, pruning, and meticulous care,
妥善的浇水、修剪、悉心呵护
the world can maintain its beauty just like this.
世界也能永远一直这么美丽
Welcome, Thorn Princess.
欢迎 荆棘公主
The heather smells wonderful!
石楠花闻起来好香喔!
The leaves of the burning bush are vibrant too. Look.
卫矛的叶子颜色也有很多种 你看
You surprised me!
真是吓了我一跳!
Pardon me. I was worried that having a family may have dulled your senses.
抱歉 我本来担心有了家庭之后 你身手是不是会变迟钝
But it seems like you have not changed.
但看来你一样身手矫健呢
I can now entrust you with our new client with confidence.
那么我可以放心把新客人交给你了
Please do! I will gladly get rid of the bad guys anytime you wish!
包在我身上 我随时 都很乐意替您杀死那些坏蛋!
How reassuring. But...
真是可靠 不过...
your assignment this time is to protect the client.
你这次的任务是担任护卫
Protect?
护卫?
ORIGINAL WORK BY TATSUYA ENDO SERIALIZED ON SHUEISHA'S SHONEN JUMP PLUS
(远藤达哉原创作品 连载于集英社漫画杂志《SHONEN JUMP PLUS》)
Do you know of the Gretcher family?
你知道葛瑞切家族吗?
MISSION:30 PLAN TO CROSS THE BORDER
剧名:任务:30 越境作战
For generations, they have been a great force, running this country's
是世世代代秉持道义的作风
underworld in an honorable way.
掌管我国黑社会的一大势力
Due to an internal conflict,
不久前 因为他们内部的纷争
their boss and his two sons were recently killed.
他们的老大跟他两个儿子被杀了
The only surviving members of the Gretcher family
葛瑞切家族仅剩的幸存者
are Olka Gretcher and her son.
就只有奥尔嘉葛瑞切以及她儿子
Currently, they're taking shelter at a hideout,
目前他们正在一处藏身处避难
but the man who took over the organization,
但是篡夺组织的那个男人
Leonardo Hapoon, is in a frenzy searching for them.
莱昂纳多哈普正疯狂地搜捕他们
He put a huge bounty on their heads,
他祭出了高额的悬赏金要他们的人头
and according to rumors, assassins all over the world are on the move.
谣传说全球的职业杀手都开始行动了
We have agreed to help her seek asylum in a foreign country.
我们已经答应帮他们 逃到第三方国家寻求庇护
Our escape route is the sea.
逃脱路线是走海路
In order to go unnoticed by the coast guards,
为了躲过沿海警卫的耳目
they'll travel as passengers until the ship is offshore.
他们会以普通旅客的身分 乘船前往外海
Then we'll rendezvous with a ship heading to their destination.
然后再跟另一艘船会合 前往目的地国家
I want you to stay by their side until they're safely handed over.
我需要你一直跟着他们母子俩 直到他们顺利搭上那艘船
I'm to protect these mafia family members from assassins.
我要从众多杀手中保护黑手党成员...
It would be best if all goes as planned without encountering any enemies.
如果不用正面迎敌的话是最好
You'll be there just in case anything happens.
那么你的存在就只是为了以防万一
I was indebted to the boss who was regrettably killed.
不幸遇害的前任老大对我有恩
So please accept this job.
所以我希望你一定要接受这份任务
But what about my work at the city hall?
但...市政厅那边的工作怎么办?
And if I'll be away for a few days, I have to think of an excuse to say to my family.
要离开几天的话 也得跟家里那边交代才行
Don't worry about that.
这点你不用担心
I had them come up with a bogus plan to have you
我已经让人拟订了伪装计划
travel as part of your work for the city hall.
你会以市政厅的工作为由随行
The director will fill you in on the details later on.
等会儿部长会告诉你详细情形
I'm counting on you, Thorn Princess.
一切就拜托你了 荆棘公主
To keep this world a beautiful place.
为了让这个世界继续美丽下去
I understand. I will do my best!
我明白了 我会全力以赴的!
It's my first job in a long time. I have to give it my best.
好久没接到工作了 我必须拿出最佳状态才行
- Yuri! - Sis!
-尤里! -姐姐!
I didn't expect to run into you on this train.
没想到你会搭这班电车呢
Oh yeah... I'm returning from a business trip.
哦 是啊 我刚出完公差回来
I was arresting a political prisoner.
其实是去逮捕政治犯了
- Good work. You want to come over to eat? - Really?
-辛苦了 要不要过来吃饭? -可以吗?
Oh... never mind.
不 还是算了
Lotty's waiting for you, and I still have work left to do.
劳迪在家里等你吧 而且我也还有工作要做
Like organizing wiretapping data.
整理监听纪录之类的
When will you become friendlier with Loid?
你什么时候才要 跟劳埃德先生好好相处?
- Never. - Are you eating well?
-不可能啦 -你有好好吃饭吧?
Make sure you don't leave your socks lying around.
袜子脱掉了也不要随地乱丢喔
Sis, I'm not a little kid anymore.
姐姐 我已经不是小孩子了
Right. You're right.
是耶 说得也对
Forg Square.
佛尔格广场
I can't be dependent on you forever.
毕竟我不能总是跟姐姐撒娇嘛
Although I did the other day.
尽管不久前我才撒娇过
Make sure you rely on me when you need help, Sis.
姐姐才是 遇到困难时尽管来找我喔
I'll kill Lotty for you in a second.
如果问题出在劳迪身上 我马上处死他
See you.
那之后见了
Sis!
姐姐!
Yuri is all grown up now.
尤里现在真的长大了
That's right.
是啊
He has a job now, and he's able to support himself.
他现在有工作了 也有能力养活他自己了
He doesn't need my help anymore.
再也不需要我照顾他了
Is there a reason for me to continue this job
我还有理由继续从事
as an assassin?
职业杀手吗?
Oh, what a shame! Seventh place is a scrubby brush!
真可惜 七等奖是一把硬毛刷!
Dammit.
可恶
Come on, everyone! It's Central Mall's biannual mega raffle!
大家快来喔 中央购物中心半年一次的大抽奖喔!
Get one raffle ticket for every 30 dalc you spend!
购物满30达尔克就送抽奖券一张!
The grand prize is two tickets for a voyage on a cruise ship.
首奖是豪华邮轮之旅双人套票喔
Come and try your luck!
快来试试手气吧!
Father,
父亲
Anya wants to get on that ship and go on a big adventure.
阿尼亚想搭上那艘船 展开大冒险
I see. How brave of you.
这样啊 真是勇气十足
Give tickets to this brave hero.
把抽奖券给这位勇者吧
I only have one ticket.
我只有一张喔
Oh, a shame! Sixth place is a luxurious scrubby brush!
真可惜啊 六奖是高级硬毛刷!
What the hell? Is the grand prize really in there?
搞什么?真的有最大奖吗?
The grand prize is still available.
最大奖还没被抽走呢
Bunch of idiots. Keep spending money for the grand prize you'll never get!
一群笨蛋 就继续为了 永远抽不到的最大奖花钱吧!
This cruise trip is mine!
邮轮之旅是我的!
I even made preparations beforehand.
我可是做好了事前准备了
I know. We have to pretend we're strangers.
我知道 我们得装成陌生人
The grand prize ticket is glued to the top of the box.
最大奖粘在箱子上面
No one else will ever get it.
谁都不会抽到的
It's my privilege as an employee here!
这可是员工的特权!
I can't wait for us to go on this trip, Cindy!
真是令人期待啊 辛迪!
I'm not that interested in a cruise, but I guess I'll go if it's free.
我其实对邮轮没兴趣 免费的话倒是可以去看看
Hey there little girl. It's your turn.
小妹妹 轮到你了
Here you go. I hope you win!
来 祝您抽中大奖喔!
Hurry up and draw a blank, you little brat.
赶快把烂奖都抽走吧 小鬼
The lady behind you is going to win the grand prize.
你后面的大姐姐等着要抽最大奖
- We've got a winner! - How?!
-抽中最大奖啦! -怎么会?
Loid and Anya, I'm back.
劳埃德先生、阿尼亚 我回来了
Listen to this, Mother!
听我说 母亲!
LUXURY CRUISE
(豪华邮轮)
Anya won a trip on a cruise!
阿尼亚抽到坐船旅行!
- What? - She won the grand prize at a raffle.
-什么? -她在抽奖活动抽到最大奖
Amazing!
好棒喔!
It's too good to be true. I almost suspect a trap.
实在好得太不真实 我都怀疑是不是陷阱了
Father is suspicious of everything.
父亲什么都要怀疑
It's a ticket for two, so would you like to go with her, Yor?
这是双人套票 机会难得 约尔小姐愿意和她一起去吗?
I have work, after all.
毕竟我还有工作在身
I'm super excited because I've never been to the ocean before!
阿尼亚没看过大海 好兴奋!
Bond, you're staying home.
邦德 你留下来看家
Princess Lorelei cruise?
罗乐莱公主号?
I'll be going on this cruise ship for work!
是我这次出公差要坐的船!
- What? - And this also departs on Friday.
-什么? -而且一样是周五出发的船班
- You're going on a ship for work? - Yes, um...
-你要搭邮轮出公差? -对啊 就是...
The city is trying to invite a famous department store,
市政府打算 邀请知名百货公司过来驻点
so we're entertaining their VIP.
所以我们要招待他们的高层出游
I see. It must be a part of the recent urban development.
这样啊 是最近都市开发的一部份吧
In reality, I have a job to protect important people from assassins.
其实我是因为有工作 要保护重要人士不被杀手杀害
This job is a battle of assassins!
杀手战斗的工作!
If by chance, they both get on this ship,
万一他们跟我搭上同一艘船的话
it will be difficult for me to do my job.
这样工作起来会很不方便
What should I do?
怎么办好呢?
Don't make things difficult for Mother. Cancel your excur-gen.
不要给母亲找麻烦 不要短“腿”旅行了
Why should I care? I want to cruise the ocean.
阿尼亚才不管咧 我就是要在海上晃来晃去
Deep down, you agree with me too.
其实你心里也是这么想的吧
You're right. I might be able to kill two birds with one stone if I help Mother.
没错 说不定能顺便帮母亲 那就一举两得了
Be honest with yourself. You've been wanting to go out to sea.
对自己诚实点吧 你一直都想要去看大海啊
Anya wants to go on a ship! If I can't, I'll turn into a delinquent!
阿尼亚想要坐船! 不然我就要变坏坏!
Oh boy.
真伤脑筋
I'll go to work tomorrow and see if I can take some time off.
明天上班 我再去问问看能不能请假
No problem at all.
完全没问题
I'll make arrangements so you can take time off from the hospital.
我会安排好 让你可以跟医院那边请假
Thank you.
谢谢了
Stop fooling around. Work until you're worn thin!
少开玩笑了 给我工作到粉身碎骨为止!
There's talk that she got scolded by the main office for overworking us.
听说高层训过她 要她别太过压榨我们这些下属
Caring for Anya's needs and education is part of Operation Strix.
照顾阿尼亚的需求跟教育她 也是“枭”行动的一部份
Agent Twilight,
特工黄昏
go and successfully complete the mission of rest and time off.
好好完成名为休假的任务吧
Excur-gen, excur-gen!
短“腿”旅行!
It's been so long since we've been on an excur-gen as a family!
好久没有 作为一家人短“腿”旅行了!
Yes, although I'll be working.
是啊 尽管我是去工作的
- Be careful. - If only I wasn't assigned this job.
-小心点 -要不是接到这份工作
Then the three of us could've enjoyed a family vacation.
那我们三个就能好好享受家庭旅行了
What am I saying!
我在说什么啊!
I'm misplacing my priorities!
这样不是本末倒置了嘛!
What's wrong, Mother?
怎么了 母亲?
That's our station!
我们要在那里下车!
But if I make this...
假如可以让这次任务...
my last job as Thorn Princess...
成为荆棘公主最后一份工作的话...
It's so big!
好大喔!
- I'm so excited! - Calm down.
-好兴奋! -冷静点
I'll be going now to meet up with the people from city hall.
我现在先去跟市政厅的同事会合
I'll contact you whenever I can.
可以的话我再联系你们
I'm sorry to be having fun on our own.
真是抱歉 我们丢下你自己去玩
Good luck, Mother!
加油 母亲!
Pool! Circus!
游泳池!马戏团!
Games room! And...
游戏中心!还有...
Ocean!
大海!
Father, this ship is amazing! I can sense a great adventure!
父亲 这艘船好厉害! 阿尼亚感觉会有大冒险!
Well, it's a luxury liner built to honorably represent Ostania.
毕竟这是赌上东国名誉的豪华邮轮
- Let's go explore! - After we leave our luggage in our room.
-赶快去探险吧! -先把行李放到房间再说
I can't wait for the suite room!
住套房 好兴奋!
It seems like I stepped into a prison cell by mistake. Wrong room.
阿尼亚不小心走到牢房了 不是这间
It's the correct room. This is what a third-class cabin is like.
是这间没错 三等舱就是这样
Please wait until next time to enjoy Anya's adventure.
阿尼亚的大冒险 请期待下一部作品
You won this free trip at a raffle. Don't be too picky.
这是抽奖抽到的免费行程 别挑了
This is Anya's first time sleeping on a bunk bed!
阿尼亚第一次睡上下铺!
- I'm gonna take the top bunk! - Go ahead. Don't fall.
-阿尼亚要睡上铺! -随便你 不要摔下来了
Yor and her co-workers must be in the first-class cabin.
约尔小姐跟她同事一定在头等舱吧
- That's not fair! Mother is living it up. - Well, she has to entertain guests.
-不公平 母亲自己享受! -毕竟她有招待的工作嘛
Allow me to introduce myself.
容我自我介绍一下
I'm Matthew McMahon, the Director of Policy at Berlint City Hall.
我是巴林特市政厅 政策部的马修麦克马洪
This is Heymann and Vides from the Business Development Team.
这边是产业振兴部的黑曼恩跟维德斯
And this is Forger.
还有这位是福杰
Furseal Grey from Development Department at Arhaus Department Stores.
我是雅尔豪斯百货 店铺开发部的佛西尔葛雷
This is my wife, Shaty.
这位是内人 夏蒂
- Sorry for bringing along our child. - No problem. Enjoy your family trip.
-不好意思 小孩也带过来了 -哪里 请好好享受家庭旅行
Any female assistance you require.
如果需要女性同仁协助
- Please ask Forger. - Thank you.
-随时可以吩咐这位福杰小姐 -谢谢
She's Ms. Olka from the Gretcher family.
她就是葛瑞切家族的奥尔嘉夫人
She's so different from her picture.
跟照片上看起来判若两人
She must have changed her appearance. Nice to meet you.
一定是改变了外貌吧 请多多指教
It's nice to meet you. So this is Olka's guard?
请多多指教 这位就是奥尔嘉大姐的护卫?
She looks frail, but will she be okay?
看起来很柔弱 没问题吗?
This Princess Lorelei cruise
这次罗乐莱公主号
is a short two-night, three-day voyage that tours around the near-by islands.
会在邻近岛屿进行 为期三天两夜的短程旅行
We hope the Grey family will be able to enjoy a relaxing trip.
希望葛雷先生与您太太 能享受这次的旅途
It's nothing compared to your
虽然比不过百货公司
department stores, but there is a shopping mall on this ship as well.
不过这艘船上也设有购物中心
Would you like a tour?
要不要去逛逛呢?
These two are actual personnel who know nothing about us.
这两位员工对我们一无所知
- Sure, thanks. - I'll decline.
-好 -我就不去了
- I'll stay here and look after my baby. - Okay.
-我留在这里照顾孩子 -这样啊
Then I'll leave Forger here with you.
那我就让福杰留下来陪您
- This way, Mr. Grey. - But, um...
-这边请 葛雷先生 -咦?那个...
Will she be okay with just one guard?
她只有一名护卫没问题吗?
Shouldn't we all stick together?
应该一起行动比较好吧?
She'll be safe as long as she stays inside the room.
只要她待在房间里 就绝对不会出事
We'll first inspect the ship.
先去检查船的环境吧
Please rest assured.
请尽管放心
She's very strong.
她很强的
Your job this time is to protect Olka and her son.
你这次的工作是保护奥尔嘉母子
We've learned that there are numerous assassins out to get them.
我们收到情报指出 现在有很多杀手都想要他们的命
If need be, please get rid of the enemies.
有必要的话 就消灭敌人
I'm counting on you, Thorn Princess.
就拜托你了 荆棘公主
All the entry and escape routes have been checked beforehand.
所有入口跟逃生路线 都已经提前查看过了
But I can't rest assured until I confirm it myself.
但我没有亲自确认的话就无法放心
Although I'm sure the Director checked it himself.
虽然我相信部长应该已经亲自看过了
You're really in that line of work, huh?
你真的是在那边工作呢
Oh? Yes.
咦?对啊
Which line of work?
哪边啊?
You're Ms. Olka, right?
那个...您是奥尔嘉夫人吧?
Yes. Although I rather not be called by that name while on this ship.
对 但在这艘船上 请尽量不要用那个名字喊我
I apologize!
对不起!
- Mama! - Oh no, he woke up.
糟了 他醒了
I'm so sorry!
真是对不起!
Mama!
妈妈!
Isn't it funny?
真是不可思议
Even though I changed my appearance, he still knows that I'm his mother.
就算我的容貌变了 他还是知道我是他的母亲
Perhaps it's my voice or my scent, or because his vision isn't fully formed.
可能是通过我的声音或气味吧 又或许只是因为他的视力还不健全
It makes me a little sad that no one
不会听到有人说孩子长得像妈妈
will ever say that we look alike. But I don't care about that now.
老实说我真有点难过 不过现在那都不重要了
He took after his dad, so I guess it doesn't matter either way.
这孩子本来就比较像他父亲 所以也无所谓了
Your husband was a very nice man.
您的丈夫是很优秀的男人
Oh, he's just a member of our crew.
刚刚那个人只是我们其中一名成员
He's just playing a part. But he's a nice guy, nonetheless.
只是让他扮成我的丈夫而已 不过他确实是个好人
My husband was killed along with my father and brothers.
我的丈夫 跟他的亲兄弟都已经惨遭毒手了
That's why my son is all that I have left.
所以我就只剩下这个孩子而已
I'm sorry... I had no idea.
对不起 我...
It's okay. It's the fate of being born into a gangster family.
没关系 这是生于黑道家族的宿命
But I'm tired of it.
但是 我有点厌倦这种生活了
I don't need the name or the inheritance.
我不需要组织的名气 也不要财产
I just want to live a quiet life.
我只想安稳度日
It's okay. What's wrong?
乖喔 不哭 这是怎么了?
Ms. Bodyguard, can I ask you for a favor?
护卫小姐 可以麻烦你一件事吗?
Ever since the dispute began, I've been forced to stay hidden.
自从纷争开始到现在 我被迫过着掩人耳目的生活
I want to spread my wings a little.
我只是想稍微喘口气
I want to let him enjoy the outside air as well.
也想让这孩子呼吸一下外面的空气
But um... we need the Director's permission...
可是...我们需要部长同意...
Please. Just for a little while.
拜托你 只要一下下就好了
My enemies don't know what I look like now.
对方应该不知道我现在的长相
And they don't know that I'm on this ship to begin with.
应该也不知道我在这艘船上的事
Plus, if anything happens, you'll be here to protect me, right?
而且万一发生了什么 你也会保护我们吧?
I understand. Just for a little while.
我明白了 只能一下下喔
Wouldn't you attract more attention with that behavior?
你那样鬼鬼祟祟的 应该更惹人注意吧?
Well, it's true that I'm watching out for the bad guys...
不是的 虽然我的确是在戒备敌人...
But...
只不过...
- Your family is also on this ship? - Yes.
-你的家人也在这艘船上? -是的
My husband and daughter.
我先生跟我女儿
Father, we need to hurry up and finish exploring, or this ship will sink.
父亲 我们要赶快完成探险 不然这艘船就要沉了
It won't sink! Watch what you say!
船才不会沉!不要乱讲话!
But really,
但说真的
this ship is unbelievably large. It seems like famous people are on board too.
这艘船实在很大 看来船上也有很多有名人物
I should prepare for a possible terrorist attack,
我应该做好准备 以免遇上恐怖份子攻击
and look out for suspicious people, and check the configuration of this ship.
得留心可疑人物 好好查看这艘船的构造
I must be aware of when and where certain people gather...
弄清楚何时何地 哪些人会聚集在一起...
Father isn't having fun.
父亲都没有在玩
Oh crap. Old habits die hard!
糟了 职业病发作
Successfully complete the mission of rest and time off.
好好完成名为休假的任务
I must rest! I need to do my best and make full use of this time off!
我要休息! 这次我必须竭尽全力休息!
- Let's go watch a show! - Father is so serious.
-我们去看表演吧! -父亲好认真
Why did you even bring them here?
你怎么会带他们上船呢?
Well, it all happened by accident.
这个纯属巧合
My family doesn't know about this line of work.
我的家人并不清楚我的工作
So if fighting ever erupts, and they see me, it would be trouble...
要是爆发战斗 被他们看见就麻烦了
Well, it'd be trouble if other passengers were to see me too.
其实被其他乘客看到也会很麻烦
If they're in the third-class cabin,
他们在三等舱的话
we won't bump into them if we stay in the first-class area.
只要留在头等舱就不会遇见他们
That's true, but...
话是这么说没错...
You're really concerned about this. Your family is just for your cover, right?
你真的很担心他们 他们只是用来伪装的家人吧?
Yes... you're right...
说得...对呢...
I guess you're right...
您说得没错...
That's right! Let's go outside right away!
也对 我们赶快去外面吧!
Wait.
等一下
I'll let you borrow this.
这个借你
It feels amazing.
感觉真好
This is...
这个...
Now we look like two mothers here on vacation.
现在我们看起来 就像来度假的两位母亲
It's better than your suit. Even if your husband were to
这样比穿套装好多了 就算你的丈夫
see you from far away, he won't be able to tell it's you.
远远看到你也无法认出你来
You're right.
确实是这样呢
What a calm breeze.
多温和的风啊
There's no sign of land in sight.
已经看不到陆地了
You're right.
是啊
I left so many things behind.
我舍弃了好多东西
Oh, is he getting cold?
是不是变冷了?
Let's head back.
我们回去吧
Um... Ms. Shaty.
那个...夏蒂太太
I will do my best! I will protect you both,
我会加油的!我会保护两位
and carry out my duty!
完成我的使命!
- Besht. - Yes! I will do my "besht"!
-“甲”油 -是 我会好好“甲”油!
Gram.
格拉姆
That's his name. The same name as my father.
这是这孩子的名字 跟我父亲的名字一样
- That's his real name. - Gam.
-是他的真名 -格拉姆
Nice to meet you, Gram.
请多指教 格拉姆少爷
- Want to hold him on the way back? - May I?
-回去的路上要不要换你抱他? -可以吗?
I'll be careful not to break his bones.
我会小心不弄断他的骨头的
I'm sorry! Here, take him back, Ms. Shaty!
对不起!我把他还给您吧 夏蒂太太
- Where's the bathroom? - The show's at five.
-卫生间在哪? -表演是五点开始
- Let's go to the bar. - Wow!
-去酒吧 -好棒喔!
- I can go shopping! - Dad!
-我可以去购物! -爸!
What is it? Don't go too far.
怎么了?不要跑太远喔
- I will win the next election for sure. - No, those stocks are...
-下次选举我一定会赢 -不行 这支股票...
Oh man, I hear the lock to the emergency door is broken.
真伤脑筋 逃生出口的门锁坏了
- I was about to be left behind. - Next time for sure...
-我本来已经被丢在后面了 -下次一定要...
This is delicious.
这个好好吃
- Company A's product is... - Therefore...
- A公司的产品... -因此...
- E-226, all clear. - Oh, seriously...
- E226 正常 -真的吗...
Gram... His name...
格拉姆 这孩子的名字...
The same name as my father.
跟我父亲的名字一样
Where should we go tomorrow?
明天要去哪里?
Nice to meet you, Gram.
请多指教 格拉姆少爷
I'm sorry! Here, take him back, Ms. Shaty!
对不起!我把他还给您吧 夏蒂太太
Shaty... Shaty...
夏蒂...
Shaty Hutton. Room 2125.
夏蒂胡顿 2125号房
Shaty Copeland. Room 3064.
夏蒂科波兰 3064号房
Shaty Grey. Room 8053.
夏蒂葛雷 8053号房
MISSION:31 THE FEARSOME LUXURY CRUISE SHIP
(任务:31 战栗的豪华邮轮)
Subtitle translation by: Lili Morita
字幕翻译:洪贞韵